Preliminary Guide to the Washington State University Audio/Video Materials 1950s-2005
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Preliminary Guide to the Washington State University Audio/Video Materials
1950s-2005
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives and Special Collections
UA2022-13
Washington State University
1 Linear foot of shelf space 1 Box
The collection comprises audio and video produced by, for, or about Washington State University, dating from the 1950s to 2005.
Washington State University as an institution dates to 1890, when it was authorized by the newly-formed State of Washington. WSU's history is documented in numerous pieces of film and video, the oldest known being film footage of the Jan. 1 1916 "Rose Bowl" football game played in Pasadena, California.
The collection comprises audio and video produced by, for, or about Washington State University, dating from the 1950s to 2005. The majority of the media is from the 1980s, 1990s, and 2000s. The majority of the materials came in individually or in small sets. Included in the collection are news stories, promotional videos, and recordings of significant performances, events, and speakers.
This is an unprocessed collection. Any arrangement reflects either a pre-existing order from the records' creators or previous custodians, or preliminary sorting performed by staff.
This collection is open and available for research use. Please be aware that WSU MASC may or may not have the capacity to digitize all formats present.
The materials in this collection have come into the Archives in dribs and drabs since 2019. Some acquisition information remains physically with the items, but many of them simply show up without a source.
This accession will remain a spot where a/v materials, whose provenance seems unimportant, are accumulated until such time as they merit processing.
WSU holds audio/video materials in a variety of locations, including the public stacks. A very similar set to this, a set of WSU videos from diverse sources, is Washington State University Audio/Video Materials 1930-2005 (Archives 349).
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Washington State University -- Records and correspondence; State College of Washington -- Records and correspondence; State College of Washington
Universities and colleges -- Washington (State) -- Pullman
Colleges and Universities; Washington (State)
- WSU Football., circa 1950s-1960s (Box 1)
  1 6” reel audio tape
- High School Equivalency Program (HEP) recruiting film., circa 1960s (Box 1)
  1 9” 16mm film.
- PhD commencement gowns., 2012-2013 (Box 1)
  2 DVDs
- Bus wrap unveiling., undated (Box 1)
  1 DVD.
- Bucky! (Buckminster Fuller talk)., 1972 January 13 (Box 1)
  2 CDs.
- Academic Disasters panel., 1981 April 19 (Box 1)
  1 audio-cassette.
- WSU Football., 2005 September 09, November 12 (Box 1)
  2 MiniDVs. Recorded by Tim Marsh.
- Scenic Palouse “dub from KWSU VP”., undated (Box 1)
  1 u-matic ¾” video tape.
- Camp Larson video, shot by KREM-TV., 1996 July 18 (Box 1)
  2 Betacam SP videotapes.
- “Camp Larson tape 4”., undated (Box 1)
  1 S-VHS videotape.
- New Student Video., 2000 Fall (Box 1)
  1 VHS
- Unidentified WHETS., undated (Box 1)
- Gibson Distinguished Volunteer Award 2001. (Box 1)
- Gibson Distinguished Volunteer Award 1996. (Box 1)
- Lecture: Rand Lewis., 1998 October 29 (Box 1)
  1 VHS. Donated M. Tomacheva, 2019-07.
- Lecture: Xinyang Wang., 1994 February 22 (Box 1)
- Lecture: Noriko Kawamura., 1994 February 15 (Box 1)
- Lecture: Thomas Lumpkin., 1994 March 08 (Box 1)
- Mini-University Tape 2., 1991 November 15 (Box 1)
- Rawlins open forum., undated (Box 1)
- APAC dialogue with Rawlins., undated (Box 1)
- HEP 30 year graduation #1 and #2., 1998 April 25 (Box 1)
  2 VHS tapes.
- WSU HEP graduation., undated (Box 1)
  1 Flashdrive
- Return to Mt. St. Helens, KIRO News., 1990 (Box 1)
- Release of mink liberated from WSU fur farm by ALF., 1991 August 03 (Box 1)